RIZ MANTER

PENULTIMATE YEAR STUDENT



riz.manterllegmail.com



linkedin.com/in/riz-manter-69ba8a1a0/



rizmanter11.github.io/rizmanter/



0450038579

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a current Computer Science and Commerce student at UNSW graduating at the end of 2022. Most of my programming experience lies with C, Java, Python and Javascript. Although I have engaged with databases, networks, OO design and functional programming, I am always keen to step outside my comfort zone.

EXPERIENCE

JP Morgan Virtual Internship Experience Program
Dec 2019 - Jan 2020

Participated in the open access JP Morgan Virtual Internship Experience Program with Forage. Tasks Completed Include:

- Creating an interface using HTML/CSS and Python with stock price data feed and set up a system for analysis of data.
- Implementing the Perspective open source code in preparation for data visualisation.
- Increasing convenience through displaying data visually through the Perspective software.

EXTRACURRICULARS

CSE Society Media Subcommittee Member Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

- Supported the executive leadership and subcommittee directors in creating and maintaining media content in the form of videos, podcasts, publications and articles.
- Helped conceive and develop a website in collaboration with the Software Projects subcommittee to collate all of our content into one place.

CSE Society Hackathon lite 2020

- Designed and implemented website to autonomously allow interns and work integrated learning participants to upload work, for companies to review and check progress in response to the COVID restrictions.
- Assisted in the implementation of the backend using Python, Flask API and React to store authentication, messaging and review data.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

University of New South Wales (UNSW)

B. Computer Science & B. Commerce Jan 2019 - present

Business Economics and Computer Science Major

- Programming Coursework: OO Design & Programming, Algorithms and Programming Techniques, Data Structures, AI, Database Systems.
- Commerce Coursework: Intro to Business Databases, Game Theory, Managing Organisations and People, Business Finance.

TECHNICAL & PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Java, C/C++, Python, MIPS, React
- Linux, Windows, Git
- Oracle SQL, HTML/CSS, Excel
- Communication, Leadership, Conflict Management

PROJECTS

Personal Website

HTML, CSS

Designed and developed a single page HTML and CSS website to showcase my personal projects and blog. (https://rizmanterll.github.io/rizmanter/)

Roman Civilisation Game

Java, JavaFX

- Implemented a Risk style video game using Java and JavaFX that applied a turn-based military/economic strategy game that allowed players to invade and attack virtual provinces.
- Engaged in agile processes to create a dynamic backend and interface that adapts to the players moves and visualises it in real time.

Sudoku Solver

Python, Pygame

- Implemented a backtracking algorithm in Python that visually solves or lets you play a sudoku game.
- Integrated a GUI using pygame to graphically implement the solver.